<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="formatting_cell_alignment" xml:lang="en-US">
    <title>Cell Alignment</title>
    <shortdesc>How to align the content in cells, horizontally, vertically, and even
        rotated.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <critdates>
            <created date="2017-08-31"/>
            <revised modified="2017-08-31"/>
        </critdates>
        <metadata>
            <keywords>
                <indexterm>Cell<indexterm>alignment</indexterm></indexterm>
                <indexterm>Alignment<indexterm>cell</indexterm><indexterm>horizontal</indexterm><indexterm>vertical</indexterm></indexterm>
            </keywords>
        </metadata>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p>A cell has a vertical and horizontal alignment. By default, the vertical alignment is the
            bottom alignment for all cells. The default horizontal alignment is left-align for text,
            right-align for numbers and center-align for logical values ​​(TRUE or FALSE ). You can
            change all these alignments as you can see in the following figure.</p>
        <fig>
            <title>Examples of alignments</title>
            <image keyref="Cell_Alignment_Example">
                <alt>Examples of alignments</alt>
            </image>
        </fig>
        <p>To apply a particular alignment, first select the cell(s) and then click one of the
            buttons in the group <menucascade>
                <uicontrol>Home</uicontrol>
                <uicontrol>group Alignment</uicontrol>
            </menucascade>.</p>
        <fig>
            <title>Group alignment on the ribbon</title>
            <image keyref="Ribbon_Group_Alignment">
                <alt>Group alignment on the ribbon</alt>
            </image>
        </fig>
        <p>The buttons don't need an explanation. When you hover the mouse over a button you get
            some explanation.</p>
        <p>In the example, the following options are used.</p>
        <dl>
            <dlentry>
                <dt>Vertical alignment</dt>
                <dd>The options are top, middle, bottom. Applied in the cells A1:A3.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
                <dt>Horizontal alignment</dt>
                <dd>The options are left, center, right. Applied in the cells A5:A7.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
                <dt>Indentation</dt>
                <dd>The options are increase indent, decrease indent. Applied in the cells
                    A10:A12.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
                <dt>Orientation</dt>
                <dd>With this button, you get some predefined options. Applied in the cells D13:F13
                    and in B14.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
                <dt>Wrap Text</dt>
                <dd>The text appears on multiple lines in the cell. For this, the row height will be
                    made larger. A long text will take less horizontal space. Applied in D3:F3.<note
                        type="attention">If all wrapped text is not visible, the reason could be
                        that the row is set to a specific height. To allow the row to adjust
                        automatically and show all wrapped text, choose <menucascade>
                            <uicontrol>Home</uicontrol>
                            <uicontrol>Format (group Cells)</uicontrol>
                            <uicontrol>AutoFit Row Height</uicontrol>
                        </menucascade>.</note></dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
                <dt>Merge &amp; Center</dt>
                <dd>Joins the cells into one larger cell and centers the content in the new cell.
                    This is often used to create labels that span multiple rows or columns. You can
                    join cells both horizontally and vertically. Applied in B14:B16.</dd>
            </dlentry>
        </dl>
    </conbody>
</concept>
